

CONTACT

Phone:

NL: +31644525213

LT: +...

Email:

vidasbace@gmail.com

Website:

bacevidas.com

LinkedIn:

Vidas Bacevičius

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Python

Java

Javascipt

React

Vue.js

Node.js Docker

PostgreSQL

Git/Gitlab

Linux

PERSONAL SKILLS

Communicative Fast learner Reliable Professional Taking initiative

VIDAS BACEVIČIUS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ABOUT

I am a communicative software engineer and a recent Computer Science graduate. Taking initiative and determined, I enjoy learning new technologies and do not hesitate to ask for help if I encounter a problem beyond my scope of expertise.

Interested in: Cloud Computing, Site Reliability Engineering, DevOps

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Nasdaq | Full-time | June 2021 - August 2021

Joined a team and worked on a real-life product being delivered to a foreign stock exchange. Built and tested Java backend validators, created frontend React components, debugged existing Java code and CI/CD pipelines. Participated in daily scrums, sprint plannings and retrospectives.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

TU Delft X | Part-time | May 2019 - Present

Responsible for creating and maintaining projects related to TU Delft X's event booking systems. Created Live Gym Tracker. Recently rewrote the backend of the system to adapt to a new REST API. Maintaining both frontend and backend of the main site's Event Schedule, Event Display, Pricing and Information tabs, Live Gym Tracker.

EDUCATION

MASTERS OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Instituto Superior Técnico | 2021 - 2022 5 Master's Degree courses during exchange programme

BACHELOR'S DEGREE OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Delft University of Technology | 2018 - 2022 GPA: 8.0

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

FITNESS TRACKER

Created a Live Gym Tracker for TU Delft X's website that allows users to see live data about current number of people in the gym, as well as previous trends, letting them choose their preferred time of visiting the gym. Before 2020, it existed on the landing page of TU Delft X. Made in Vue.js. Server logic built with Axios (Node.js), database created with PostgreSQL.

BILTER FUBBLE

Our team of four project members and myself created and deployed a music exploration game designed to encourage users to explore music beyond their preferred tastes. The process of discovering new music genres was gameified and users were rewarded points and achievements based on the variety of genres they explored. Made in Javascript over the course of two months while following the SCRUM framework.